Ronit Singh

Contact No: +917003622801, +917044132607

Website : https://imronit2001.github.io/ronit/

Address: H/No 182/1, Sthirpara Road, P.O – Mondalpara,

Dist- North 24 Paragana, Jagadal, Pin- 743127, Kolkata, West Bengal, India

Email Id: ronitsingh7003@gmail.com, ronitsinghpersonal@gmail.com

Objective

Full Stack Web Developer with 2.5+ years of experience in building dynamic web applications using modern technologies. Seeking to contribute technical skills in both frontend and backend development to a forward-thinking company, while continuing to grow and innovate.

Current Status

Currently working as a Software Developer at Triophase Global Pvt Ltd with 2.5+ years of experience in full stack web development. Skilled in creating scalable web applications using modern technologies. Also freelancing, delivering innovative tech solutions.

Educational Qualification

Degree	Year of Passing	Institution	Aggregate % / CGPA	Board / University
Madhyamik	2017	Kankinara Arya Vidyalaya	58.14	W.B.B.S.E
Higher Secondary	2019	Kankinara High School	74	W.B.C.H.S.E
B.C.A	2022	Techno India Hooghly Campus	9.71	M.A.K.A.U.T
M.C.A	2024	Techno College Hooghly	9.13	M.A.K.A.U.T

Subjects of Interest

- ❖ Data Structure and Algorithms (C, C++, Java and Python)
- Full Stack Web Development
- ❖ Relational Database Management System



Technical Skills

❖ Programming Language : C, C++, Java, Python

***** Web Development

Frontend Development: Html, Css, Javascript, React.JS, Next.JS

Bootstrap, Tailwind Css, Jquery

Backend Development: PHP, Laravel, Django, Express Js, Node Js

Databases : MySQL, MongoDB, Firebase

DevOps : Git, Github, Linux, Hostinger, Vercel, Docker
 Microsoft Office : Word, Excel, Powerpoint (2007,2013,2019,365)

Academic Projects

Frontend Projects: HTML, CSS, Javascipt, Bootstrap

Technical Club of college

https://rajendrakrshaw.github.io/Cybertronix/

❖ Text Utils | React Js

https://github.com/imronit2001/Textutils-React

❖ News Monkey | React Js

 $\underline{https://github.com/imronit2001/NewsMonkeyApp-React}$

❖ I-Notebook | MERN

 $\underline{https://github.com/imronit2001/iNotebook-React}$

❖ Text Utilizer | Django

https://github.com/imronit2001/TextUtils-Django

❖ Number Shifting Game | C Language

https://github.com/imronit2001/Number-Shifting-Game

Backend Projects: Php, Laravel, MERN Stack

- E-Classroom Management System (TIHCollegeSpace) | PHP | Clg Minor Pr http://collegespace.epizy.com/index.html
- Online Banking Management System (Suraksha Bank) | Laravel | Clg Major Pr https://github.com/imronit2001/suraksha-bank
- E-Commerce Platform (My-Cart) | React JS & Laravel | Clg Minor Pr MCA https://github.com/imronit2001/Mycart-Laravel
- Spark Quest 3.0 | Laravel | Clg Tech Fest Website https://www.linkedin.com/posts/imronit_webdevelopment-laravel-php-activity-7107397692628099074-XY1B/
- Techhub | Laravel | Clg Major Pr MCA
 https://www.linkedin.com/posts/imronit_services-mernstack-nextjs-activity-7255969991374602240-4Hwy/

Work Experience

❖ Triophase Global Pvt Ltd. (Feb 2024 – Present)

Skillset: PHP, Mysql, Next.Js, Jquery, Bootstrap, Docker

Role : Software Developer

❖ Nextgen Techno Ventures Pvt Ltd. (May 2022 − Feb 2024) 1 Year and 9 Months

Skillset: PHP, Laravel, Django, Mysql, Firebase, MERN, Jquery, Tailwind Css, Bootstrap

Role : PHP Intern, SDE Trainee, Web Team Lead

Details : Creating Responsive Web Pages, Restful Api, Integrating Api, Db Management, Project

Deployment, Conducting Interviews

Courses & Certification

- Web Design for Everybody: Basics of Web Development & Coding | Coursera | University of Michigan https://coursera.org/share/c2144c3e17327a20b5f8d4aac15b3869
- **❖ Programming For Everybody (Getting Started with Python)** | Coursera | University of Michigan

https://coursera.org/share/e6ed0863d065fa800ff272d5b9968c28

- Python Data Structures | Coursera | University of Michigan https://coursera.org/share/458913760f6c3613da2403b511c8bb57
- ❖ The Joy of Computing using Python | NPTEL | IIT Madras https://imronit2001.github.io/ronit/python-nptel.jpg
- A Crash Course on Python | Coursera | Google https://coursera.org/share/07f5dea62a6d2e7fc4d0d46171196b8e
- ❖ C for Everyone : Programming Fundamentals | Coursera | University of California https://coursera.org/share/fdc2f44e160354055479aa807cc4cacd
- ❖ A Job Ready Bootcamp in C++, DSA and IOT | iNeuron https://cdn.ineuron.ai/learn/certificates/ae63f8a8-e506-4922-bb30-e55cca39e1d9.pdf
- Java Standard Edition | Mysirg https://premium.mysirg.com/learn/certificate/7398936-136789

Leadership Skills & Achievements

- ❖ Mentor of CodeChef TCH Chapter (2020-2021)
- ❖ Executive Member of Cybertronix (Technical Club of Techno India Hooghly)
- Member of Spark Quest 2.0 (Technical and Management Fest of Techno India Hooghly)
- ❖ Member of VERBANA-TIH Cultural Committee (2020-2021)
- Class Representative in College BCA and MCA (2019-Present)
- ❖ President of CodeChef TCH Chapter (2021-2022)
- ❖ Member of Antiragging Committee (2023-2024)

Personal Information

• Date of Birth : 03rd August 2001

• Gender : Male

• Father's Name : Pappu Kumar Singh

Father's Occupation : Self Employed
Father's Phone Number : +919681498621

• Languages Known : Hindi Language, English Language, Bengali Language

Date: 24th November 2024

Place: Jagadal, North 24 Paragana

Ronit Singh